Hi I'm Kelli, I'm an aesthetician and a makeup artist at Ulta Salon and Cosmetics and I'm going to show you how you can apply a powder foundation.
You have a couple of different ways that you can apply a powder foundation depending on how much coverage you want.
For a fuller coverage, you would want to apply it with a sponge.
For a lighter coverage, you would want to apply it with a brush.
So just to demonstrate, going to do a lighter coverage on one half of her face and a darker coverage on the other half.
So we're just going to dust this all over using a brush.
Just even out her skin tone.
So you can see it gives her some coverage but it doesn't necessarily give her a really full coverage.
So if I want a fuller coverage, I'm going to use a sponge.
The sponge is going to pickup more pigment and in turn give a fuller coverage.
So you can just see the difference between the two sides of her face, lighter coverage, fuller coverage.
So those are two ways you can apply powder foundation.